<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Realm Z</title>
    <link>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Realm Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 11:24:36 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://zhiqiyu.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fully-Connected Layers (FCN) in Convolutional Neural Network (CNN)</title>
      <link>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/conv-fc-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 11:24:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/conv-fc-conversion/</guid>
      <description>Recently, during a discussion with a colleague about his CNN model architecture on remote sensing image fusion task, he mentioned something that was interesting. Specifically, in his network, he used FCN implementations Keras.layers.Dense and torch.nn.Linear in his code, the input to the FCN is a 2D image with many channels with size (160, 160, channels). Traditionally, I think that to pass through a FCN layer, the neuron numbers of the first FCN layer in this case, should be 160 * 160 * channels, which basically means to flat the volume to a 1D array and feed in a traditional neural network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning Specialization Certificate</title>
      <link>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/dl-special-cert/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 17:15:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/dl-special-cert/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I have completed the 5-month journey of the Deep Learning specialization on Coursera. I enjoyed this course a lot.
Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to apply some of the idea in my research work. Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning Course Certificates</title>
      <link>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/dl-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 11:22:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/dl-certificates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good job for me to earn several deep learning related certificates under the Deep Learning Specialization on Coursera. The specialization is offered by Dr. Andrew Ng from deeplearning.ai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course assignments can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zhiqiyu/Deep-Learning-Coursera&#34;&gt;https://github.com/zhiqiyu/Deep-Learning-Coursera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following is the breakdown course certificates I earned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applied Data Science with Python Coursera Certificates</title>
      <link>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/ads-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 21:11:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/ads-certificates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good job for me to earn several certificates from the Applied Data Science with Python offered by Michigan University on Coursera!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course material can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zhiqiyu/Applied-Data-Science-with-Python&#34;&gt;https://github.com/zhiqiyu/Applied-Data-Science-with-Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Coursera Certificate</title>
      <link>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/ml-certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 20:17:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/ml-certificate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good job for me to earn the Machine Learning course certificate offered by Prof. Andrew Ng from Stanford University on Coursera!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course assignments can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zhiqiyu/Machine-Learning-Coursera&#34;&gt;https://github.com/zhiqiyu/Machine-Learning-Coursera&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperspectral Remote Sensing for Geospatial Intelligence</title>
      <link>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/hsi-geoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 17:07:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/hsi-geoint/</guid>
      <description>This article is for an assignment of GGS684 Topics in Geospatial Intelligence.
I believe the Hyperspectral remote sensing will be the game changer for geospatial intelligence. Traditional remote sensing sensors usually provide only 10s of bands that cover visible spectrum range and near infrared range. The limited number of bands lead to the relatively broad range of spectrum that a band would cover. But hyperspectral sensors greatly shrinks the spectrum range that one band cover so that each band can ’focus’ more on its designated spectrum range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emerging Future of GIS</title>
      <link>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/future-gis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 16:57:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/future-gis/</guid>
      <description>This article is for an assignment of GGS684 Topics in Geospatial Intelligence seminar. The video series mentioned in the article is the Geospatial Revolution Series made by PennState University. This video series is a good viewport of what GIS can do and how it is changing our lives.)
The Geospatial Revolution series has introduced several cases on how GIS is being used in modern societies and how it is changing the way we live and the world around us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation of GDAL and its Python Libraries on Mac</title>
      <link>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/gdal-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 17:07:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/gdal-install/</guid>
      <description>Recently I have been trying to install GDAL on my Mac and I cannot find a way to link the Python libraries to the Python program I am using so that I can import GDAL libraries by the import gdal statement in my python program.
The GDAL is designed to run in Mac OS X Terminals, but the installation include python libraries which are not automatically linked to the program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 11:31:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zhiqiyu.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Zhiqi Yu Summary Solid background in GIS and remote sensing. Strong programming background with various popular programming languages. Strong theoretical background in machine learning/data mining and practical experience in text processing and remote sensing image data processing.
Skill Sets Languages &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Python, JavaScript, Markdown, C#, Octave (MATLAB), R, C/C++
Software &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; ArcGIS, Google Earth Engine, MS Visual Studio, ERDAS IMAGINE
Libraries &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; TensorFlow, Keras, Scikit-learn, Scikit-image, Pandas, Jupyter Notebook, Matplotlib, GeoPandas, Leaflet, GDAL/OGR</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>