<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Remote Sensing on Realm Z</title>
    <link>https://zhiqiyu.github.io/tags/remote-sensing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Remote Sensing on Realm Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 15:20:20 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zhiqiyu.github.io/tags/remote-sensing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Landsat8 and Sentinel2 Image Pairs Generation</title>
      <link>https://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/landsat-sentinel-match/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 15:20:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/landsat-sentinel-match/</guid>
      <description>This notebook presents a data preparation workflow that finds same-date and overlapped Landsat8 and Sentinel2 image patches and provide a way to download the processed images to the local machine.
This is a part of the ongoing research project Landsat2Sentinel.
The whole notebook is available on my Github repository.
import ee ee.Initialize() from IPython import display import zipfile import urllib from ipywidgets import IntProgress  Function for downloading images from GEE def download_tif(image, scale, name, folder): url = ee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperspectral Remote Sensing for Geospatial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/hsi-geoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 17:07:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhiqiyu.github.io/post/hsi-geoint/</guid>
      <description>This article is for an assignment of GGS684 Topics in Geospatial Intelligence.
I believe the Hyperspectral remote sensing will be the game changer for geospatial intelligence. Traditional remote sensing sensors usually provide only 10s of bands that cover visible spectrum range and near infrared range. The limited number of bands lead to the relatively broad range of spectrum that a band would cover. But hyperspectral sensors greatly shrinks the spectrum range that one band cover so that each band can ’focus’ more on its designated spectrum range.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>